# Edvin Teskeredžić

# ABOUT ME

MoEE with a focus on Computer Science and Computer Engineering. Working as a GTA on the Faculty of Electrical Engineering Sarajevo, I have developed my interpersonal and communication skills, as well as my public speaking capabilities. Co-authoring several internationally published research papers has helped me learn to think both creatively and analytically, and to work as part of a team. My interests are wide, ranging from Software Engineering and IT, to HPC and Data Analysis. I am passionate about both software and hardware, especially FOSS. Currently interested in gaining more experience in the industry, as well as expanding my knowledge.



#### Personal Data

#### **EDUCATION**

```
2019 - 2021 Master of Electrical Engineering (major: Computing and Informatics),
University of Sarajevo
Master thesis:
'Analysis and Application of Deep Learning Methods for Solving the Problem
of Spatial Aliasing' (Advisor: Dr. Amila Akagić)

| Diversity of Sarajevo
| Bachelor of Electrical Engineering (major: Computing and Informatics),
University of Sarajevo
| Bachelor thesis:
'Overview and Application of Methods for Obstacle Detection and Avoidance
in Unknown Environments' (Advisor: Dr. Amila Akagić)
```

## WORK EXPERIENCE:

```
08/2021 - Present
                     Software Engineer - Social Explorer Inc.
                      www.socialexplorer.com
      2018 - 2021
                     (Under)Graduate Teaching Assistant - Faculty of Electrical Engineering
                      www.etf.unsa.ba
                      GTA for the course Fundamentals of Computer Networks (since 2017)
                      GTA for the course Computer Literacy (since 2018)
                      GTA for the course Digital Signal Processing (since 2018/2019)
                      GTA for the course Fundamentals of Database Systems (since 2020)
                      GTA for the course Artificial Intelligence (since 2020)
                     Duties as GTA: Overseeing/grading laboratory work, writing lab/course materials
          07/2018
                     Laboratory assistant - International University of Sarajevo
                      www.ius.edu.ba
                     Laboratory assistant for the IUS STEM Camp (Introduction to Data Science in R)
```

## LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

Fluent (with a TOEFL iBT score of 115 out of 120) ENGLISH: Fluent (with DSD certificate of C1 level of proficiency) GERMAN:

First language Bosnian:

## COMPUTER SKILLS

C/C++, C#, Python, Java, R, Matlab Programming:

Web Frameworks familiar with: Angular, React, Rails, Spring

Database: PostgreSQL, Oracle SQL Parallel Programming: CUDA, OpenCL, VHDL

AI and Data Science: NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, TensorFlow, Keras

LATEX, Open Office, MS Office, LibreOffice Type Setting: Operating Systems: MS Windows, GNU/Linux (Debian-based)

Others: ROS, x86-64 Assembler (basics), Git, Bash, Zsh

# Interests and Hobbies

AI, Embedded Systems, Computational Geometry, Graph Theory Interests:

Vice President, Embedded Systems Club ETF Positions:

HOBBIES: Pub quizzes, Sci-Fi media

## **Publications**

Papers

A. Arnautović and E. Teskeredžić, "Evaluation of Artificial Neural Network Inference Speed and Energy Consumption on Embedded Systems" 2021 20th International Symposium INFOTEH-JAHORINA (INFOTEH), East Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina, 2021, pp. 1-5, doi: 10.1109/INFOTEH51037.2021.9400658. Available at: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9400658/

E. Teskeredžić and A. Akagić, "Low Cost UGV Platform for Autonomous Indoor 2D Navigation and Map-Building Based on a Single Sensory Input" 2020 7th International Conference on Control, Decision and Information Technologies (CoDIT), Prague, Czechia, 2020.

Available at: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9263975/

E. Teskeredžić, K. Karahodžić and N. Nosović, "Comparison of the Non-Blocked and Blocked Floyd-Warshall Algorithm with Regard to Speedup and Energy Saving on an Embedded GPU" 2020 19th International Symposium INFOTEH-JAHORINA (INFOTEH), East Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina, 2020, pp. 1-5. Available at: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9066330/

Lab Modules

Co-author of laboratory exercises for the course "Artificial Intelligence" on the bachelor's degree programme "Computing and Informatics". The modules cover fundamentals of Python, deep neural networks, expert systems, fuzzy logic, genetic algorithms, and intelligent software agents. Faculty of Electrical Engineering Sarajevo, 2021. Modules are available on the course page: https: //c2.etf.unsa.ba/course/view.php?id=120

Co-author of laboratory exercises for the course "Digital Signal Processing" on the bachelor's degree programme "Computing and Informatics". The modules cover basics of signal analysis and digital image processing. Faculty of Electrical Engineering Sarajevo, 2020. Modules are available on the course page: https: //c2.etf.unsa.ba/course/view.php?id=41

Co-author of laboratory exercises for the course "Computer Literacy" on the short-cycle study programme "Software Development". The modules cover the fundamentals of GNU/Linux, IATEX, image and audio editing. Faculty of Electrical Engineering Sarajevo, 2018. Modules are available on the course page: https://c2.etf.unsa.ba/course/view.php?id=317